<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>notunremarkable</title>
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me" />
    <updated>2017-12-21T08:00:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Teejay</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 21</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-21/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-21/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-21T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/56/advent-21.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's Cybersecurity tip is: use common sense</p>
<p>We've spent a majority of the past few weeks reviewing technological tools to help keep you secure. But there's a saying that goes "built something more idiot proof and they'll build a better idiot." </p>
<p>Not to call anybody names, but a modicum of <em>common sense</em> is involved in just about everything you do in life ... including using a computer, mobile device, or the internet.</p>
<p>So, to recap some of the major points from earlier in this series, and to add a few more; here is a list of common sense tips to keep in mind while online:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Never give out personal information</strong> - except in very few circumstances</li>
<li><strong>Be careful what details you post online</strong> - don't share too much</li>
<li><strong>Pay attention to your audience</strong> - who can see your post?</li>
<li><strong>Use strong passwords</strong> - longer is better, password managers are better still</li>
<li><strong>Use multi-factor authentication</strong> - whenever and wherever you can</li>
<li><strong>Don't click links or attachments</strong> - especially unsolicited links, but verify links are legitimate if you trust the source</li>
<li><strong>Check your settings</strong> - don't stick with the default settings for any online service; double-check them</li>
<li><strong>Surf securely</strong> - don't use public Wifi and always use a VPN</li>
</ul>
<p>Bottom line is, think about what you're doing. Does it feel right? Go with your gut.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 20</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-20/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-20/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-20T15:56:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/54/advent-20.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>use HTTPS everywhere</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;I've already touched on <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/39">encryption </a>in this series, so you're aware of the importance of scrambling your data. I've also briefly touched on encryption of your <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/45">data in transit using HTTPS</a>.</p>
<p>So today's tip is a quick and easy one in which you install the <a href="https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HTTPS Everywhere</a> browser plugin provided by the Electronic Frontier Foundation.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This plugin will automatically redirect your browser traffic to secure, HTTPS-enabled servers if available or if their ruleset is in place. While not perfect, and doesn't cover every site on the internet, it still adds another level of security to your day-to-day browsing.&nbsp;</p>
<p>That's it ... that's all I've got today. Even though it's short, it's still important; so go <a href="https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">install that plugin now</a>.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 19</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-19/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-19/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-19T23:50:05-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/53/advent-19.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>manage your privacy while browsing</strong></p>
<p>I'm sure it comes as no surprise that your browsing habits are tracked regularly by multiple sites. If you look at your cookies in your browser of choice right now, there are probably hundreds to thousands of cookies stored there. Those cookies feed information back to their host about sites you've visited or preferences you've set for a specific site.&nbsp;Cookies aren't inherently bad; but there are some sites that use cookies beyond their original intent or outright maliciously.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Some might be inclined to just turn off cookies in their browser. However, then you risk losing some of the benefits of cookies. A reasonable alternative is to use one of several browser plugins to help protect your privacy. My plugin of choice is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ghostery.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ghostery</a>.</p>
<p>Ghostery is an easy-to-install browser plugin available for all the major browsers. Once installed, you will be walked through the setup. You will be asked a few questions in which you should consider your browsing habits and preferences about trackers. One of the last steps is to create an account in order to sync your settings across computers and browsers ... I've never done this if I'm honest; I just set it up again since it's so easy. But you do what is best for you.</p>
<p>Once you're setup, you'll have a little icon in your browser that will show you how many trackers and cookies are being blocked on a site. If you find a site isn't working for some reason, they may have a cookie that is required for proper use. In that case, you can click on the ghost icon and&nbsp;<strong>pause</strong> Ghostery; reload the page and verify if it's working or not. If that's the case, then you can add that site as a "trusted site" and then resume Ghostery protection.</p>
<p>That's really all there is to it. Now your browsing habits, sites you've visited, and any other online activities will be kept more private by having those trackers blocked. As I mentioned previously, Ghostery&nbsp;<em>is</em> a proprietary company, so they are likely anonymizing your data and monetizing it somehow. I'm okay with it because I receive a service from them for free&nbsp;<em>and</em> they're up front in their privacy policies how they use your information. If you're not alright with it, I recommend you find an <a href="https://prism-break.org/en/subcategories/windows-web-browser-addons/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">open source alternative</a> that has similar features.&nbsp;</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 18</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-18/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-18/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-18T12:55:36-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/52/advent-18.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>use ad-blockers</strong></p>
<p>First and foremost, I use a lot of free services on the internet. And I know many of those services rely on advertising revenue to remain in business. However, as somebody who assesses risk for a living, I look at the pros and cons of just about everything.</p>
<p>Many websites use third-party advertising engines to feed relevant advertisements to their site (relevant to the user based on many factors). These third-party advertising engines/sites may or may not vette the advertisements and many will sell your information to advertisers. Some&nbsp;of the third-party advertising sites host malware-injected advertising as well. In my opinion, there are enough risky advertisements out there to warrant using an ad-blocker in my daily use.</p>
<p>That said, I also do whitelist sites I trust and/or rely on in order to allow them to continue their business. There are many different options for blocking advertisements during your internet browsing ... let's take a look at a few of them:</p>
<p><strong>Browser plugin<br></strong>There are a lot of options for browser plugins, almost too many. The two I've used regularly with good success are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UBlock_Origin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">uBlock Origin</a> and <a href="https://adblockplus.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Adblock Plus</a>. Adblock Plus does allow some pre-vetted (and "non-intrusive" according to them) advertising through ... which is why I switched to uBlock Origin (UO); that and UO is open source. Either way, they are both available on just about every browser out there and very configurable.</p>
<p><strong>Browser</strong><br>There are even a few browsers with adblocking built right into their code. <a href="https://brave.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brave Browser</a> and <a href="https://www.opera.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Opera </a>are two big ones. Firefox Focus and Opera are both mobile browsers with built-in adblocking for browsing safely on-the-go.</p>
<p><strong>Other</strong><br>You should also consider a privacy plugin like <a href="https://www.ghostery.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ghostery</a>. This helps protect your personal information and does some ad blocking as well. I'm&nbsp;<em>almost certain</em> there will be a tip on this soon.</p>
<p>Adblocking not only has privacy and security benefits to browsing, but can also help your user experience on many sites (faster loading, for instance). Fortunately, there are a lot of tools available that make it easy to accomplish. We looked at just a few, so I hope you're installing one now if you didn't have one already.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 17</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-17/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-17/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-18T12:55:58-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/51/advent-17.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>review your connected accounts</strong></p>
<p>Many websites allow you to sign in using your credentials from another service (like Google, Facebook, or Twitter). While this is convenient, depending on what you agreed to when you connected the account, they may be seeing more information or have more access than you intend. Not only that, but these connections are sometimes set to not expire, so you give some other company access to your information long after you've stopped using their service.</p>
<p>Fortunately there's a relatively easy fix. Spend a few minutes today reviewing your connected accounts and ensure only the services you want connected stay that way. Here's how to check your connected apps in the big three:</p>
<p><strong>Google</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Visit your <a href="https://myaccount.google.com/permissions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">account permissions page</a> and sign in with your Google account</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Facebook</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Log into Facebook and go to&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Apps</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Twitter</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Log into Twitter and go to&nbsp;<strong>Settings and privacy -&gt; Apps</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>See how easy they make it? All three tell you what level of access the connected app has and when it last connected. You might be surprised how many connections you have. When I first started doing this years ago, I had apparently connected an app I only ever used once and granted it full permission to my Twitter account (back before Twitter was better about limiting access of third party services); and it had had those permissions for almost a year. Oof.</p>
<p>Short and sweet today, but you will definitely feel better knowing you've cleared house of some backdoor access to your social media and private information.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 16</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-16/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-16/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-18T12:56:18-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/50/advent-16.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/48">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>be careful what you post</strong></p>
<p>It seems obvious to say you don't want to give away personal information online, but it's surprising the information you can find about people with a simple search.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When you think about "personal information", a few obvious things come to mind: name, birth date, phone number, SSN, etc. However, there can potentially be a lot of information that&nbsp;<em>alone</em> isn't a big deal, but when put together with other information, can comprise a bigger picture of your identity.</p>
<p>In fact, depending on your location (US regulations differ from EU&nbsp;regulations) or even industry (health standards differ from financial standards). In general though, the more information the&nbsp;<em>bad guys</em> have about you, the easier it is to exploit that information. So, here are a few tips to keep your information private:</p>
<p><strong>Make sure your social networks are private</strong><br>Unless you need to maintain a public social media presence (actors, politicians, etc.), then your best security is making your activity on the network&nbsp;<strong>private</strong> or&nbsp;<strong>secret</strong>.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Keep your profile information limited</strong><br>Even if you&nbsp;<em>do</em> need to maintain a public social media presence, you should limit the amount of information you share in your profile. The less you post, but better.</p>
<p><strong>Verify your friends</strong><br>It's easy to follow anybody who follows you first.&nbsp;But making sure you're only friending people you&nbsp;<em>actually</em> know provides another layer of security when sharing potentially personal information becuase you more likely trust somebody you actually know.</p>
<p><strong>Validate your sharing settings</strong><br>Take a look in your application's settings to see what features they offer to limit who sees your information and how it gets shared. For instance, on Facebook you can limit how people even find you or whether they need to know your email address or phone number before finding you.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Think about what you're sharing</strong><br>Take a few seconds to re-read and/or think about the information you're sharing. Is it something you wouldn't mind everybody in the world knowing? If so, maybe you should modify what you post.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are about a hundred more ways you can keep your information private. But what it all boils down to is common sense. You've certainly read somebody else's social media post and thought&nbsp;<em>I wouldn't have shared that much information</em>. Hopefully you will take a few minutes to check your sharing settings and feel safe about what you're putting out there to the world.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 15</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-15/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-15/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-15T09:31:32-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/49/advent-15.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>be careful in email</strong></p>
<p>In reality, you should be careful and pay attention to all the information you post or share, links you click, or attachments you open online; not just in emails. But most people use email everyday for both personal and business reasons as well as communicating with people you don't know. Most other digital communication is in a controlled environment or with a limited audience. Additionally, it's very easy for <em>"bad guys"</em> to exploit email because of the relative anonimity, it's easy to reach wide audiences, and easy to&nbsp;spoof. Therefore, it's very important to protect yourself and be vigilant when using email.</p>
<p>Here are a few things to pay attention to and some guidelines to follow for your inbox:</p>
<p><strong>Don't trust&nbsp;links</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do you trust or know the person/service that sent the link?</li>
<li>Were you expecting a link? For instance if you started a password reset for an account and need to verify your email address</li>
<li>Check to make sure the link text matches the actual URL (mouseover or right-click to see the actual link URL)</li>
<li>Make sure it's a secure link - HTTPS</li>
<li>Make sure it's a trusted domain or from a service you actually have an account with</li>
<li>Double-check the full URL - mybank.com is not the same as mybank.adifferentserver.com</li>
<li>When in doubt, always open a browser and go directly to that service's website rather than click the link; if you receive an email from your bank stating you urgently need to open the link, then the same message should be in your account on their website&nbsp;... <strong>ALL</strong> good services do this</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Don't trust attachments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do you trust or know the person/service that sent the attachment?</li>
<li>If your web client doesn't scan attachments for malware automatically, either save the file locally and scan or scan directly in the web client before opening</li>
<li>Ensure the program you use to open the attachment opens it in "safe" mode - Adobe Reader and all Microsoft Office programs can be configured to disable running scripts or other malware processes, for example</li>
<li>When in doubt, reach out to the person who sent the attachment and ask if it's safe - preferably contact them on a different channel (call/text), or</li>
<li>Better yet, just delete the email</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Be vigilant of information you give out<br></strong>Even if an email doesn't include an attachment or link, the person sending it might be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">phishing</a> for information. Don't give out any usernames, birth dates, SSNs, or other sensitive information. Pay attention to who they are and what they're asking. If you wouldn't give information to a stranger face-to-face, then you shouldn't through email. And remember that it's very easy to spoof email information, so it can look like it's coming from somebody legitimate. Sometimes it doesn't hurt to verify you're having an actual conversation with the right person ... or better yet, is email the best place for that conversation? Maybe a phone call, text, or some other form of communication would be better.</p>
<p>Hopefully these tips will help you feel a little safer using your inbox and can avoid malware or security breaches of sensitive information through email (and other digital communication).</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 14</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-14/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-14/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/48/advent-14.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>protect your lockscreen</strong></p>
<p>I don't even need to mention how important protecting your mobile device is ... this is the <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/46">third</a> <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/47">day</a> of tips dedicated to them. And while it's convenient to have notifications displayed on your phone's lockscreen so you can quick check a text or email without unlocking the device, it's also a bit of a privacy and security risk.</p>
<p>It's not unimaginable to picture a scenario in which a temporary password or something is emailed to you and shown on your phone's lockscreen; or even something as benign as a phone number being texted to you. Both scenarios can potentially reveal information you either want private or can be used against you.</p>
<p>The benefit of not sharing private information, especially if you lose your mobile device, far outweighs the minor inconvenience of having to unlock your device to view a notification. Since I'm certain you agree, here are the steps to modify (or at least review) your notification settings on the two latest platforms:</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Visit&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; location -&gt; Lock screen preferences</strong>; from here you can turn off or "hide sensitive notification content"</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Visit&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Notifications -&gt; Show Previews</strong>; from here you can turn off or only show previews "when unlocked"</li>
</ul>
<p>Your device is now locked down with a secure passcode, easy to find or remotely lock if you lose it, and sensitive and private information won't be shown on the lockscreen. Kudos to you for your security-consciousness.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 13</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-13/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-13/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/47/advent-13.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>enable "find my phone" features</strong></p>
<p>This will be quick and to the point. As <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/46">I mentioned yesterday</a>, we pretty much carry our lives on our mobile devices. If you've never lost a phone, or even just misplaced it, count yourself lucky; it is&nbsp;<em>not</em> a fun feeling.</p>
<p>Fortunately, most mobile operating systems have features available, built into the device, to help you find your phone if you lose it. Here are the steps for the two latest mobile operating systems:</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; location -&gt; Find My Device</strong> and turn it "on"</li>
<li><em>note:</em> you may need to download the "Find My Device" app from the Google Play store first</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Your Apple ID account -&gt; iCloud -&gt; Find My iPhone</strong> and turn it on</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you are able to visit the <a href="https://www.google.com/android/find" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Find My Device</a> or the <a href="https://www.icloud.com/">Apple iCloud</a>&nbsp;page on a web browser, sign into the same account you're logged into on the phone, and then remotely lock, locate, and/or play a sound on your phone. This is handy if the phone was left somewhere or just lost in the house.</p>
<p>See?&nbsp;Easy-peasy lemon squeezy. See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 12</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-12/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-12/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/46/advent-12.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>lock your mobile device</strong></p>
<p>Most of us carry (or have access to) everything in our phones: bank account, personal contacts, social media, and more. You're basically walking around with a mobile computer, and should treat it with the same care and consideration as your laptop or desktop.</p>
<p>It's likely you already have a passcode on your mobile device; most of them require you to set one up these days when you first get it. Unfortunately, it's probably also only a four digit passcode. Did you know that with the right hardware, your four digit code can be brute force hacked in just&nbsp;<em>four days</em>?</p>
<p>The more digits in your passcode, the harder it is to crack. At the very least, just take your four digit passcode and double it. Turning&nbsp;<strong>1234</strong> into&nbsp;<strong>12341234</strong>&nbsp;makes a brute force crack go from about four days to almost&nbsp;<em>six years</em>! Of course ... you use a better passcode than&nbsp;<strong>1234</strong> though, right?!</p>
<p>So right now, if you don't have a passcode, set one up. If you do, but it's less than eight digits, update it!</p>
<p>Now, before you jump to setting up your fingerprint or facial recognition ... a word&nbsp;of warning. Keep in mind that all biometric data can be spoofed or forced (coersion or legally) somehow. That doesn't mean you shouldn't&nbsp;use it at all;&nbsp;I do. It certainly is more convenient to place my fingerprint on the scanner than it is to type in an eight digit passcode everytime I want to do something secure. However, you need to personally weigh the pros and cons of that convenience versus the potential drawbacks. If you&nbsp;<em>do</em> continue with using your biometrics (fingerprint and/or face), remember that every time you reboot your device it will require you to re-enter your passcode.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Well, today was short and sweet and now your device is&nbsp;<em>years</em> more secure than it was previously. See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
