<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>notunremarkable</title>
    <link href="https://notunremarkable.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://notunremarkable.github.io" />
    <updated>2017-11-06T21:18:06-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Teejay</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://notunremarkable.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Old Skool </title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://notunremarkable.github.io/old-skool/"/>
        <id>https://notunremarkable.github.io/old-skool/</id>
            <category term="Misc"/>
            <category term="Links"/>

        <updated>2017-11-06T20:28:43-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/3/2017-11-06-post-oldskool.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>Ran across some fun little images that somebody posted. These instantly transported me to my childhood ... anybody else?</p>
<p><img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/3/2017-11-06-oldskool-01.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480"></p>
<p><img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/3/2017-11-06-oldskool-02.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="536"></p>
<p><img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/3/2017-11-06-oldskool-03.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="616"></p>
<p><img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/3/2017-11-06-oldskool-04.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480"></p>
<p>source (plus more images): <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/tBJ0c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://imgur.com/gallery/tBJ0c</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The one in which I test everything</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://notunremarkable.github.io/the-one-in-which-i-test-everything/"/>
        <id>https://notunremarkable.github.io/the-one-in-which-i-test-everything/</id>
            <category term="Design"/>
            <category term="Blogging"/>

        <updated>2017-11-06T19:51:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/2/2017-11-05-post-testing.jpg" alt="" />
                <h2>Testing Everything</h2>
<p>I want to look at the features of Publii and see how well the WYSIWYG editor works (until I can figure out how/if to use <strong>Markdown</strong>).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Humankind. Be both.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That's a blockquote ... in case&nbsp;<em>you</em> can't <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">figure it out</span> tell.&nbsp;</p>
<p class="align-center">Center aligned ... obvi.</p>

<p class="align-left">Reasons I'm liking this so far:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keeps all my files local</li>
<li>Easy to setup and use</li>
<li>Fun to tinker (but works right out of the box so you don't have to)</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="align-center" src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/2/be-a-fruit-loop.jpg" alt="Fruit Loop" width="236" height="295"></p>
<p>Images are easy to upload ... I'll have to see where it stores them and how it looks in the post.</p>
<hr>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cOMSIlsA9o0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<p>I recently re-signed up for a Todoist subscription. The free version works and has plenty of features, but I want the filters and labels ... which means I pay for the premium. This dude has a lot of great videos on how to get the most out of Todoist too.</p>
<p>OK, there are a lot of great features. I found in the settings where I was able to change the local location of the files/site too. So now it's sitting in my OneDrive local folder and will get backed up to the cloud as my backup. <em><strong>W00T!</strong></em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Publii and Github pages</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://notunremarkable.github.io/publii-and-github-pages/"/>
        <id>https://notunremarkable.github.io/publii-and-github-pages/</id>
            <category term="Technical"/>
            <category term="Blogging"/>

        <updated>2017-11-06T19:52:21-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://notunremarkable.github.io/media/posts/1/2017-11-05-post-github.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>I have been reading about the comeback of static blog sites. During the course of my research, I thought it might be more inline with the way I like to blog and do things. My current content management system (CMS) is Wordpress. It has a lot of features, thousands of plugins to extend functionality, and even more themes (paid and free). There is a thriving Wordpress community, so it's very easy to get up and running ... literally click a button to install in some instances.</p>
<p>At any rate, it's practical but not *fun* for me. I'm a tinkerer and like to know how things work. I've also been working with straight HTML for hundreds of years ... well, that's how it feels sometimes; so there's a familiarity and comfort level I like.</p>
<p>So a static site generator (SSG) basically is a framework that helps you create a whole site of static pages. It will build the "home page" with the list of posts, track tags, authors, etc. It's usually easier to theme as well. I tried using Pelican, a Python based framework; but had some issues in Windows. For the sake of time, I started searching for other options rather than troubleshoot more (which I may still go back and do eventually).</p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://getpublii.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Publii</a>. It's a downloadable tool with a GUI that helps you manage your whole site (or sites). I've connected it to Github pages to host for free and am now testing it out. So let's see how this goes! In all honesty, I was hoping for a Markdown editor, just because I like that sort of thing, but this is very nice and easy so far ... we'll see.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
