<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>notunremarkable</title>
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me" />
    <updated>2017-12-09T10:04:03-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Teejay</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 09</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-09/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-09/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/43/advent-09.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>secure your home wifi/router</strong></p>
<p>If you don't have high-speed internet at home, today's tip probably won't be for you. Also, how do you survive?&nbsp;Anyway, here are some things you can do to shore up your home wifi router:</p>
<p><strong>Change Default Password</strong>. Your Internet Service Provider (ISP) probably preset the administrator username and password. Log in (using their instructions provided) and change the password. If you have an option to change the admin username, do that too! Many times, the default username/password are universal and can be found on the internet.</p>
<p><strong>Enable Network Encryption</strong>. In order to keep your home network traffic secure and private, you'll want to turn on WPA or (ideally) WPA2 encryption. Each router has different instructions on how to do this.</p>
<p><strong>Change Default SSID</strong>. Your Service Set ID (SSID) is the name of your network and might be set to the manufacturer's default name. Pick a new, unique name for your network to show that you take the time to configure your network properly.</p>
<p><strong>Disable Broadcast SSID</strong>. Now that you know the name of your network, turn off broadcast so that people can't easily find your network without knowing the name. While this doesn't necessarily protect your network, it does hide it making it a little harder to crack.</p>
<p><strong>Advanced Options</strong>. Depending on your level of comfort, consider turning on the firewall (if it's not already) and/or enabling MAC address filtering. These steps will ensure nobody can remotely connect to your router (other than your ISP) and only devices you specify will even be able to connect to the router.</p>
<p>You've taken huge steps in securing your home network and should be able to rest relatively easy knowing you're browsing safely.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 08</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-08/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-08/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/42/advent-08.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>change your passwords</strong></p>
<p>Ideally you've chosen and setup a <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/41">password manager</a>. If not, this part will not be as easy ... but still necessary. Changing your passwords&nbsp;will also be a time consuming process but&nbsp;one that should be ongoing in your life.</p>
<p>As stated previously, the old school of thought was that you should change your password fairly frequently, like every 90 days. New wisdom says only change your password when there's been evidence of a breach of login information. I'm a little more conservative and don't see the harm in changing your passwords annually ... especially if you're using a password manager; it will do all the heavy lifting for you! I feel annually strikes a good balance and minimizes data loss in case of a breach.</p>
<p>If you do use a&nbsp;password manager, it can generate a password with any parameters you give it. I recommend 16-20 characters (or more if the site supports it) and a mix of as many different types of characters as possible. If you have the option to&nbsp;<strong>not</strong> use dictionary or pronouncable words, I suggest you do&nbsp;that too just for an extra layer of security. Again, the point is to have ridiculously hard passwords to guess, and let your password manager remember it for you. Try to manually remember <strong>iJBblxg6@%Ur95VNj0uz</strong> for just one site and now think about&nbsp;how many sites with which you actually have an account.&nbsp;<em>Just don't forget your master password!</em></p>
<p>If you're not using a password manager, then try to stick with memorable passphrases or even just use three random words that you'll remember. Most sites allow all ASCII characters, even spaces, so&nbsp;<strong>round blue bananas</strong> would be a valid password and easier to remember than the password generated <strong>iJBblxg6@%Ur95VNj0uz</strong>. Of course, it likely won't meet the password requirements of most sites ... so you'll have to mix it up a little and&nbsp;<em>still</em> remember it.</p>
<p>Also important, use a different password/passphrase for every site or service with which you have an account (which is <em>very</em> easy to do with a password generator ... are you seeing a theme yet?). For example, if your credentials are stolen in a data breach at&nbsp;Uber.com, <em>hypothetically,</em>&nbsp;and you reused that&nbsp;password everywhere, then the hackers potentially have your login information for every site you visit. Use a different password everywhere (or one master password for your password generator ... okay I'll stop now)!</p>
<p>Now you know how to make a good password; so&nbsp;get out there and do it. In my opinion, you should make a habit of changing your password every year on every site you visit. Put it in your calendar and then just try to break it up over the course of a week or so. Make the effort to visit 5-10 of your sites per day and change your account passwords. It shouldn't take more than 15 minutes to go through that many&nbsp;sites, so you won't spend more than a couple hours over the course of one week per year. That's a pretty small investment to help keep your digital data secure.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 07</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-07/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-07/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-07T09:51:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/41/advent-07.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>use a password manager</strong></p>
<p>For a long time, you probably heard that your password should be a mix of upper, lower, special characters, and numbers and that you needed to change it every two or three months. Oh, and you can't re-use any of the last 30 passwords you've ever used or use any part of a real word or any other number of ridiculous requirements.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fortunately, convential wisdom has changed. Analysis of a decade's worth of data showed that those super complex, constantly changing passwords didn't do much to help. Instead, the new guidelines recommend being more <em>user</em> friendly (hooray!). Long passwords with complexity is still important, but testing those passwords against lists of dictionary passwords and known compromised passwords. And of course, you still need unique passwords for every account you have.&nbsp;In reality, people can't remember that many unique passwords&nbsp;... even with <a href="https://www.passwordping.com/surprising-new-password-guidelines-nist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"looser" guidelines</a>. That's where password managers come in.</p>
<p>The idea of a (good) password manager is that you only need to remember your secure&nbsp;<em>master password</em> and let the password manager handle remembering all the passwords for your various accounts. This frees up your mind to remember one&nbsp;truly secure password.</p>
<p>There are several well-known and respected password managers out there, and each has its strengths and weaknesses. While there are a lot of options for password managers (Dashlane, LastPass, 1Password, etc.), the basic functionality of them is similar. Your passwords are stored, encrypted by your master password, either in the cloud or locally to your computer.&nbsp;I've used&nbsp;<a href="https://www.lastpass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LastPass</a>&nbsp;for the last seven years or so. LastPass&nbsp;only encrypts/decrypts my passwords locally, so there's no worry about a breach on their system. I&nbsp;haven't had any issues with performance, and the convenience of having my passwords on my computer and on my mobile device has saved me more than once. Bonus, LastPass supports <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-06">2FA</a>.</p>
<p>One last thought, I recommend you use a password manager&nbsp;that has a browser extension available. This allows the password manager to fill in form and password information directly on websites you visit. This makes it even more convenient to browse while still staying secure. If you have any specific questions about LastPass or setting (or choosing) your password manager, ask in the comments below.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 06</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-06/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-06/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-06T16:37:07-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/40/advent-06.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>enable multifactor authentication (MFA) or two-factor authentication (2FA)</strong></p>
<p>You're already familiar with authentication, which is proving you are who you say you are. The most popular way to authenticate to a service or system online is using an email address and password. These are considered "something you know." To make authentication more secure, we need to add another factor ... like "something you have" or "something you are."</p>
<p>"Something you are" would be biometrics (like facial recognition on Android and FaceID on iPhone). "Something you have" would be enabling a limited time passcode or requiring you to approve a login remotely from your mobile device ... often by sending you a limited time token through text which you then enter on the site. The thought being that hackers might have your username and password, but they can't get that limited time token without having physical access to your mobile device or computer.</p>
<p>Most services these days can enable some sort of 2FA or MFA. I'll walk you through setting up both a code generator app and 2FA in Twitter. I will use <a href="https://authy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Authy </a>for this example, but there are several other options including Google Authenticator and Microsoft Authenticator.</p>
<ol>
<li>Install Authy and setup your account using your mobile device number (or login to your existing account)</li>
<li>Log into Twitter and visit&nbsp;<strong>Settings</strong></li>
<li>Under&nbsp;<strong>Account -&gt; Security</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://imgur.com/tmLwybB">click the button</a> that reads "Setup a code generator app"</li>
<li>On <a href="https://imgur.com/UhgSfEO">the popup window</a>, you will either copy-and-paste the Secret Key or scan the QR Code with Authy</li>
<li>Authy will generate a six-digit code that is good for 30 seconds; copy that code and paste in the&nbsp;<strong>Security Code</strong> box in the Twitter popup and click "Done" to complete the setup</li>
</ol>
<p>Now every time you log into Twitter (only on a new device or if you logged out on your existing device) you will be prompted for your email address and password as well as a six-digit code generated by Authy.</p>
<p>Take 30 minutes or so to visit the settings in all your favorite apps to setup 2FA and you can feel safe in the knowledge that even if your username, email, and/or password are breached that your accounts are still safe.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 05</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-05/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-05/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-05T21:17:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/39/advent-05.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>encrypt everything</strong></p>
<p>Encryption seems like a scary topic to a lot of people; and if you get into the weeds of the algorithms used and salts and hashes ... it certainly can be. But for most people in everyday life, encryption boils down to <strong>securing data or information with a password</strong>; something everybody should already be familiar with.</p>
<p>Rather than try to espouse the benefits of encryption and debate the pros and cons, let me just say that encryption keeps data at rest protected. If you're storing unencrypted files in the cloud, and a hacker gets those files, they have all that information. If those same files are encrypted, you've made it exponentially harder for the hacker to get the information in those files.</p>
<p>In the interest of keeping this a "tip" rather than an essay, and so I don't take the thunder out of any potential future "tips" in this series, let me touch on some things you can do to encrypt your local storage and devices using built-in tools.</p>
<p><strong>Windows</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Certain versions of Windows contain Bitlocker full disk encryption; if you have this available to you ... USE IT; if not, consider upgrading to a higher version of Windows or using a third-party encryption tool</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mac OS X&nbsp;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>FileVault full disk encryption is available in&nbsp;<strong>System Preferences -&gt; Security &amp; Privacy -&gt; FileVault</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Encryption can be enabled in&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; Location -&gt; Encryption &amp; Credentials</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iOS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Encryption is enabled by default when you have a passcode enabled ... so <strong>make sure you have a passcode setup</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Please note&nbsp;that encrypting your hard drive can potentially slow down your system since it's decrypting files or drives before use. However, most modern devices are fast enough to compensate and you would only notice this on older, slower devices anyway. Also note, I didn't mention encrypted containers or third-party encryption applications like VeraCrypt, Symantec Drive Encryption, etc. These have the same effect, but aren't integrated into the operating system, so are potentially less secure&nbsp;... but also have their valid uses.&nbsp;If you want more information about these tools, ask below.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 04</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-04/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-04/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-05T21:16:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/38/advent-04.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>backup your devices</strong></p>
<p>If you've never experienced a hard drive crash on your computer or your mobile phone completely dying and you lose everything on your device ... consider yourself lucky. We put a lot of information, time, and effort into our devices, and if we ever lose them it can potentially be catastrophic.</p>
<p>Fortunately, it can be&nbsp;quite simple to backup your devices and your data. Unfortunately, I can't give a "one size fits all" solution here. I can provide you some guidelines&nbsp;and give you my personal setup though which will hopefully point you in the right direction to start backing up your computer and/or mobile device.</p>
<p>The first thing to remember about backups is the <strong>3-2-1 rule</strong>. Have at least&nbsp;<strong>3 copies&nbsp;</strong>of your data, on&nbsp;<strong>2 media</strong> types, and keep&nbsp;<strong>1 offsite</strong> copy.</p>
<p>How you decide to do that will depend on what you are backing up and how your system is configured.&nbsp;Here's how I handle it:</p>
<p>My important files are stored locally in My Documents on my computer hard drive then&nbsp;synced to a cloud drive automatically. Additionally, I have an external hard drive I plug in manually at least once per week and run Windows' File System backup at that time. So, I have three copies (one local, one online, and one on an external drive) on at least two types of media (hard drives and cloud drive) and one offsite (stored on the cloud provider servers). This same setup can be reproduced in Mac OS X with any cloud drive and Time Machine.</p>
<p>As for your mobile device ... I suggest either the cloud drive or frequent, manual backups to your computer. My photos are the only thing&nbsp;on my mobile that I fear losing;&nbsp;so I have automatic backups to Google Photos enabled (iPhotos will do the same thing on iPhone ... but with limited cloud space). In general, you need to ask yourself what you wouldn't want to lose&nbsp;and go from there.</p>
<p>I know it can feel overwhelming, espeically if you're not doing anything at the moment.&nbsp;So try signing up for a free cloud drive (OneDrive, Google Drive, iCloud, etc.) and just copy your "documents" folder to that drive right&nbsp;now. Or buy a 1TB USB drive (there are lots of great holiday deals, but typically can be found for under $50) and plug it into your system and copy everything over. Do that and you're already halfway to being fully backed up!</p>
<p>This is certainly a bigger "tip" than can be dealt with in this one short post. So feel free to ask specific questions in the comments and maybe I can help set you on a better path.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 03</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-03/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-03/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-05T21:16:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/37/advent-03.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>review your computer's privacy settings</strong></p>
<p>It's no secret that companies gather information about their customers. The problem is when we don't pay attention and let them gather everything about us and our habits. While their service may be great, and their intentions innocent, if they've got that information then somebody with not-so-innocent intentions can get that information; you have no control over how well those companies protect your information.&nbsp;</p>
<p>While it is easier than ever before to gather private information about people, it's also fairly easy to restrict that information (location, contacts, etc.). It might not be possible to restrict some information, depending on the device or application. In fact, restricting some information actually breaks the intended use of the application (imagine trying to use your Maps app without granting it location use ... possible, but not as intended). Therefore, it's worth taking 15 minutes or so to review your privacty settings to make sure you're comfortable with the amount of information you're sharing.</p>
<p>Here's how to do that on the more&nbsp;popular platforms:</p>
<p><strong>Windows 10</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Privacy</strong> and there are several menus worth of information to review&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Mac OS X High Sierra</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; Privacy -&gt; Privacy</strong> to review all your privacy settings</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>First you'll want to check your Google privacy settings by visiting&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Google -&gt; Personal Info &amp; Privacy</strong> or visiting&nbsp;<a href="https://myaccount.google.com">https://myaccount.google.com</a>&nbsp;in a browser while signed in with your Google account</li>
<li>Then you'll want to check&nbsp;<em>App</em>&nbsp;settings by visiting&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Apps &amp; Notifications -&gt; App permissions</strong> to review which apps have phone, camera, location, etc. permissions</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Privacy</strong> to review all your privacy settings</li>
</ul>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 02</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-02/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-02/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-05T21:16:31-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/36/advent-02.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>use anti-virus and anti-malware</strong><br><br>Adding another layer of security is installing an anti-virus <em>AND</em> an anti-malware program on your computer <em>AND</em> your phone. Macs, Windows, iPhones, Androids &hellip; all of them&nbsp;are&nbsp;potentially vulnerable. Also, no single anti-virus program can catch everything, but something is better than nothing. Plus, there are so many free options available, it's almost sinful not to install one.<br><br>So, what's the difference between anti-virus and anti-malware? A Virus is&nbsp;a specific type of malware designed to spread (like a biological virus). Malware is the general term for anything bad that gets installed on your device (spyware, adware, viruses, trojans, etc.). You're probably asking why you would need two programs installed if anti-malware includes anti-virus capabilities. There are two reasons &hellip;<br><br>First, no single provider can catch everything. Every provider of anti-virus or anti-malware software handles scanning and detection in a different way. By having two different pieces of software installed, you're adding another layer of protection.<br><br>Second,&nbsp;anti-virus tools typically run all the time, scanning files and your computer on a regular basis. Anti-malware tools typically run on-demand, when you want to check something specific. <br><br>So, do yourself a favor and find a decent anti-virus and anti-malware program. I currently use <a href="https://www.avg.com/en-us/free-antivirus-download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AVG </a>for Anti-virus (for Windows and Android) and <a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/">Malwarebytes </a>for anti-malware. There are plenty of both anti-virus and anti-malware options available though.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 01</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-01/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-01/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-05T21:16:19-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/35/advent-01.jpg" alt="" />
                Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>update your devices</strong><br><br>The most effective way to stay safe is to run the latest patches and software updates on your computer and mobile devices. While we hear all the time about zero-day vulnerabilities, most exploits happen because of known vulnerabilities that have been in the wild for a while. Having the latest updates and patches will protect against the known exploits. Having automated updates enabled will help protect against zero-day vulnerabilities because you'll be updated as soon as your provider has a fix!<br><br>Fortunately, most device makers have made this process almost mindless. Your take-away today should be to check your computer and/or phone to make sure you're up-to-date AND you have automated updates enabled.<br><br>Here's how to do that on some of the more popular platforms:<br><br><strong>Windows 10</strong><br>
<ul>
<li><em>Operating system&nbsp;</em>updates are done through <strong style="font-size: inherit;">Settings -&gt; Update &amp; Security</strong><span style="font-size: inherit;"> and just verify your settings (active hours, restart options, etc)</span></li>
<li><em>Apps downloaded through the Microsoft Store</em> are done through <strong>Microsoft Store -&gt; Settings</strong> and make sure "Update apps automatically" is turned on</li>
<li><em>Apps downloaded manually</em> will need to be updated through the settings in those apps</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Mac OS X High Sierra</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Both <em>Operating System</em> and <em>app</em> updates are done through <strong>System Preferences -&gt; App Store</strong> and make sure "Automatically check for updates" (with appropriate preferences) is checked</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Operating System&nbsp;</em>automatic updates are enabled by default, but you can verify by going to <strong>System -&gt; System update</strong> to see the last date and time the phone checked</li>
<li>To make sure your <em>apps</em> are updated, visit&nbsp;<strong>Play Store -&gt; Settings -&gt; Auto-update apps</strong> and select the appropriate choice (wifi only or at any time)</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Operating System</em> updates are in <strong>Settings -&gt; General -&gt; Software Update</strong>; these are automatically enabled, but you can verify here</li>
<li><em>App</em> updates are enabled in <strong>Settings -&gt; iTunes &amp; App Stores</strong> and toggle "Updates" to on</li>
</ul>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent Calendar</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-intro/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-intro/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-08T22:55:05-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/34/advent-intro.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>Starting on Friday, December 1, I'm going to post a series of security tips to help people learn to keep themselves safe on their computers, on their phones, and online.<br><br>While I'm using the "advent" aspect of a child's advent calendar, these aren't religious-based or meant to imply anything other than the use of a cute ploy to capture your interest and attention. <br><br>Security is no joke though and requires you to be active in the process. One doesn't leave their front door or car door unlocked and hope everything will be fine; they actively lock their doors when they leave because they know that helps keep their belongings protected. Security relies on making it more difficult for our adversaries to compromise our systems; and each thing we do adds to the complexity it takes to get into our systems or get our information. Remember that there is <strong>always</strong> a way to gain access, but we have to make them not want to gain access. There is no single solution to online and computer security.<br><br>Finally, these tips aren't anything new, they're available all over the place. My aim is to consolidate a lot of these tips and guidelines into one place, make them easy to digest, and help people learn how to be safe. I don't expect everybody to do everything. If one walks away just doing one or two new things to keep safe, then that helps.<br><br>Anyway, I hope everybody joins me for the next couple weeks and learns a thing or two along the way!<br><br>Note: I'll update this post with links to the full series along the way.</p>
<p>The calendar:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-01">Day 01</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-02">Day 02</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-03">Day 03</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-04">Day 04</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-05">Day 05</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-06">Day 06</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-07">Day 07</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-08">Day 08</a></li>
<li><a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-09">Day 09</a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
