<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>notunremarkable</title>
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me" />
    <updated>2017-12-16T08:26:36-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Teejay</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 16</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-16/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-16/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/50/advent-16.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/48">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>be careful what you post</strong></p>
<p>It seems obvious to say you don't want to give away personal information online, but it's surprising the information you can find about people with a simple search.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When you think about "personal information", a few obvious things come to mind: name, birth date, phone number, SSN, etc. However, there can potentially be a lot of information that&nbsp;<em>alone</em> isn't a big deal, but when put together with other information, can comprise a bigger picture of your identity.</p>
<p>In fact, depending on your location (US regulations differ from EU&nbsp;regulations) or even industry (health standards differ from financial standards). In general though, the more information the&nbsp;<em>bad guys</em> have about you, the easier it is to exploit that information. So, here are a few tips to keep your information private:</p>
<p><strong>Make sure your social networks are private</strong><br>Unless you need to maintain a public social media presence (actors, politicians, etc.), then your best security is making your activity on the network&nbsp;<strong>private</strong> or&nbsp;<strong>secret</strong>.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Keep your profile information limited</strong><br>Even if you&nbsp;<em>do</em> need to maintain a public social media presence, you should limit the amount of information you share in your profile. The less you post, but better.</p>
<p><strong>Verify your friends</strong><br>It's easy to follow anybody who follows you first.&nbsp;But making sure you're only friending people you&nbsp;<em>actually</em> know provides another layer of security when sharing potentially personal information becuase you more likely trust somebody you actually know.</p>
<p><strong>Validate your sharing settings</strong><br>Take a look in your application's settings to see what features they offer to limit who sees your information and how it gets shared. For instance, on Facebook you can limit how people even find you or whether they need to know your email address or phone number before finding you.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Think about what you're sharing</strong><br>Take a few seconds to re-read and/or think about the information you're sharing. Is it something you wouldn't mind everybody in the world knowing? If so, maybe you should modify what you post.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are about a hundred more ways you can keep your information private. But what it all boils down to is common sense. You've certainly read somebody else's social media post and thought&nbsp;<em>I wouldn't have shared that much information</em>. Hopefully you will take a few minutes to check your sharing settings and feel safe about what you're putting out there to the world.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 15</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-15/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-15/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-15T09:31:32-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/49/advent-15.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>be careful in email</strong></p>
<p>In reality, you should be careful and pay attention to all the information you post or share, links you click, or attachments you open online; not just in emails. But most people use email everyday for both personal and business reasons as well as communicating with people you don't know. Most other digital communication is in a controlled environment or with a limited audience. Additionally, it's very easy for <em>"bad guys"</em> to exploit email because of the relative anonimity, it's easy to reach wide audiences, and easy to&nbsp;spoof. Therefore, it's very important to protect yourself and be vigilant when using email.</p>
<p>Here are a few things to pay attention to and some guidelines to follow for your inbox:</p>
<p><strong>Don't trust&nbsp;links</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do you trust or know the person/service that sent the link?</li>
<li>Were you expecting a link? For instance if you started a password reset for an account and need to verify your email address</li>
<li>Check to make sure the link text matches the actual URL (mouseover or right-click to see the actual link URL)</li>
<li>Make sure it's a secure link - HTTPS</li>
<li>Make sure it's a trusted domain or from a service you actually have an account with</li>
<li>Double-check the full URL - mybank.com is not the same as mybank.adifferentserver.com</li>
<li>When in doubt, always open a browser and go directly to that service's website rather than click the link; if you receive an email from your bank stating you urgently need to open the link, then the same message should be in your account on their website&nbsp;... <strong>ALL</strong> good services do this</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Don't trust attachments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do you trust or know the person/service that sent the attachment?</li>
<li>If your web client doesn't scan attachments for malware automatically, either save the file locally and scan or scan directly in the web client before opening</li>
<li>Ensure the program you use to open the attachment opens it in "safe" mode - Adobe Reader and all Microsoft Office programs can be configured to disable running scripts or other malware processes, for example</li>
<li>When in doubt, reach out to the person who sent the attachment and ask if it's safe - preferably contact them on a different channel (call/text), or</li>
<li>Better yet, just delete the email</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Be vigilant of information you give out<br></strong>Even if an email doesn't include an attachment or link, the person sending it might be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">phishing</a> for information. Don't give out any usernames, birth dates, SSNs, or other sensitive information. Pay attention to who they are and what they're asking. If you wouldn't give information to a stranger face-to-face, then you shouldn't through email. And remember that it's very easy to spoof email information, so it can look like it's coming from somebody legitimate. Sometimes it doesn't hurt to verify you're having an actual conversation with the right person ... or better yet, is email the best place for that conversation? Maybe a phone call, text, or some other form of communication would be better.</p>
<p>Hopefully these tips will help you feel a little safer using your inbox and can avoid malware or security breaches of sensitive information through email (and other digital communication).</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 14</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-14/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-14/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/48/advent-14.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>protect your lockscreen</strong></p>
<p>I don't even need to mention how important protecting your mobile device is ... this is the <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/46">third</a> <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/47">day</a> of tips dedicated to them. And while it's convenient to have notifications displayed on your phone's lockscreen so you can quick check a text or email without unlocking the device, it's also a bit of a privacy and security risk.</p>
<p>It's not unimaginable to picture a scenario in which a temporary password or something is emailed to you and shown on your phone's lockscreen; or even something as benign as a phone number being texted to you. Both scenarios can potentially reveal information you either want private or can be used against you.</p>
<p>The benefit of not sharing private information, especially if you lose your mobile device, far outweighs the minor inconvenience of having to unlock your device to view a notification. Since I'm certain you agree, here are the steps to modify (or at least review) your notification settings on the two latest platforms:</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Visit&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; location -&gt; Lock screen preferences</strong>; from here you can turn off or "hide sensitive notification content"</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Visit&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Notifications -&gt; Show Previews</strong>; from here you can turn off or only show previews "when unlocked"</li>
</ul>
<p>Your device is now locked down with a secure passcode, easy to find or remotely lock if you lose it, and sensitive and private information won't be shown on the lockscreen. Kudos to you for your security-consciousness.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 13</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-13/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-13/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/47/advent-13.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>enable "find my phone" features</strong></p>
<p>This will be quick and to the point. As <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/46">I mentioned yesterday</a>, we pretty much carry our lives on our mobile devices. If you've never lost a phone, or even just misplaced it, count yourself lucky; it is&nbsp;<em>not</em> a fun feeling.</p>
<p>Fortunately, most mobile operating systems have features available, built into the device, to help you find your phone if you lose it. Here are the steps for the two latest mobile operating systems:</p>
<p><strong>Android O</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Security &amp; location -&gt; Find My Device</strong> and turn it "on"</li>
<li><em>note:</em> you may need to download the "Find My Device" app from the Google Play store first</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iOS 11</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Open&nbsp;<strong>Settings -&gt; Your Apple ID account -&gt; iCloud -&gt; Find My iPhone</strong> and turn it on</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you are able to visit the <a href="https://www.google.com/android/find" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Find My Device</a> or the <a href="https://www.icloud.com/">Apple iCloud</a>&nbsp;page on a web browser, sign into the same account you're logged into on the phone, and then remotely lock, locate, and/or play a sound on your phone. This is handy if the phone was left somewhere or just lost in the house.</p>
<p>See?&nbsp;Easy-peasy lemon squeezy. See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 12</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-12/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-12/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/46/advent-12.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: <strong>lock your mobile device</strong></p>
<p>Most of us carry (or have access to) everything in our phones: bank account, personal contacts, social media, and more. You're basically walking around with a mobile computer, and should treat it with the same care and consideration as your laptop or desktop.</p>
<p>It's likely you already have a passcode on your mobile device; most of them require you to set one up these days when you first get it. Unfortunately, it's probably also only a four digit passcode. Did you know that with the right hardware, your four digit code can be brute force hacked in just&nbsp;<em>four days</em>?</p>
<p>The more digits in your passcode, the harder it is to crack. At the very least, just take your four digit passcode and double it. Turning&nbsp;<strong>1234</strong> into&nbsp;<strong>12341234</strong>&nbsp;makes a brute force crack go from about four days to almost&nbsp;<em>six years</em>! Of course ... you use a better passcode than&nbsp;<strong>1234</strong> though, right?!</p>
<p>So right now, if you don't have a passcode, set one up. If you do, but it's less than eight digits, update it!</p>
<p>Now, before you jump to setting up your fingerprint or facial recognition ... a word&nbsp;of warning. Keep in mind that all biometric data can be spoofed or forced (coersion or legally) somehow. That doesn't mean you shouldn't&nbsp;use it at all;&nbsp;I do. It certainly is more convenient to place my fingerprint on the scanner than it is to type in an eight digit passcode everytime I want to do something secure. However, you need to personally weigh the pros and cons of that convenience versus the potential drawbacks. If you&nbsp;<em>do</em> continue with using your biometrics (fingerprint and/or face), remember that every time you reboot your device it will require you to re-enter your passcode.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Well, today was short and sweet and now your device is&nbsp;<em>years</em> more secure than it was previously. See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 11</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-11/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-11/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/45/advent-11.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is: use a VPN</p>
<p>I've already posted about the <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/39">importance of encryption</a>, but that focused on your "data at rest"&nbsp;- your hard drives and mobile device. Today's tip is about Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) which encrypts your network traffic between your computer or mobile to the end server. You're likely already a little familiar with a form of this with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL); whenever you navigate to a website using HTTPS your traffic is encrypted between the browser and the web server.</p>
<p>However, the benefit of a VPN is that&nbsp;<strong>all&nbsp;</strong>traffic is encrypted from your computer, not just the browser. Basically, the VPN software creates a tunnel between your computer and the VPN server and nobody else can view that traffic.&nbsp;Besides encrypting your data to keep hackers out,&nbsp;there are a couple other benefits to using a VPN.</p>
<p>First, your data is kept private from your Internet Service Provider (ISP) and anybody else who may try to sell your data or re-route your traffic. For example, my provider Verizon sometimes redirects my traffic to their own search engine rather than my search engine of choice. While this doesn't hurt my browsing experience&nbsp;<em>in essence</em>, it's annoying that they're intercepting my traffic and trying to monetize that when I already pay them for a service.</p>
<p>Second, you can make your computer or device appear to come from a different IP address or location. There are many reasons you might need to change your IP address or circumvent geographical network barriers, and a VPN is an easy way to do that.</p>
<p>There are a&nbsp;<strong>lot</strong> of options when it comes to a VPN provider. There are even a lot of&nbsp;<em>free</em> VPN options available. I discourage the free services simply because they have to make their money&nbsp;<em>somewhere</em>; unless they've spelled out how they're making their money, and you're okay with it. In that case,&nbsp;it might be a good start for you. Otherwise, there are a lot of affordable services that would be much more secure.&nbsp;A few things to pay attention to&nbsp;before purchasing/choosing a VPN service:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pay attention to the number of servers available to which to connect&nbsp;- more servers available means more options for you</li>
<li>Determine if geo-shifting your location is important - some services charge more for overseas or out-of-country VPN connections</li>
<li>Consider when and where you will use your VPN - is it's an "always on"&nbsp;or "on demand" type of connection; some services restrict bandwidth or only offer limited bandwidth to begin with</li>
<li>Will you use the VPN on your mobile device - if so, make sure the provider offers an app for your phone or tablet</li>
<li>Ask yourself how important privacy and plausible deniability are to you - people have their own reasons for using a VPN and all providers handle logging, jurisdiction, etc</li>
</ul>
<p>There's a fantastic, comprehensive breakdown of almost 200 VPN providers available at <a href="https://thatoneprivacysite.net/vpn-comparison-chart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That One Privacy Site</a>. There are many more factors reviewed on there, like the provider's activism for example. It's the most thorough review site I've seen and I highly recommend you check it out!</p>
<p>In the end, you have to&nbsp;<strong>trust</strong> the service you're using with your data; just like you currently trust your ISP with your data (or probably more). So, a little research is worth it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 10</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-10/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-10/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-10T09:36:36-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/44/advent-10.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>be careful with public wifi and hotspots</strong></p>
<p>Of course we're all wary of public wifi, aren't we? We&nbsp;<em>never</em> just join a hotspot at a cafe because it happens to have the same name as the cafe, right?&nbsp;</p>
<p>It takes little to no effort to setup a hotspot and advertise it to people to connect. On <em>any</em> wireless network all your traffic travels through that router or wireless access point (WAP) and can potentially be stolen. I'm not saying you can't join the cafe wifi; I'm saying be&nbsp;<em>careful</em> and pay attention before you join.&nbsp;So, in the spirit of today's tip, here are a few things to keep in mind when you're joining a public, or uncontrolled, wifi or hotspot:</p>
<p><strong>Prefer secured wifi over unsecured</strong>. If given the option of WPA or WPA2 protected network (password required), choose that over the unsecured network.</p>
<p><strong>Validate&nbsp;the SSID.</strong> Does the network name match the advertised name? If it's not advertised, ask somebody who works there.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Turn off "remember this network".</strong> You probably have "attwifi", "xfinitywifi", or "linksys" in your list of saved networks right now (or any host of other popular names). Anybody who sets up an unsecure wifi network with the same name will grab devices automatically. Turn it off and "forget" those networks right now.</p>
<p><strong>Use a VPN.</strong> Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) encrypt your traffic from the device to the server, keeping you more secure. I'm&nbsp;<em>almost</em> positive there will be another advent tip about this soon ...</p>
<p><strong>Don't share files.</strong> Most operating systems give you the option of turning off file sharing when joining wifi. Marking the connection as "public" is sometimes enough, check with your operating system to be sure.</p>
<p><strong>Avoid certain websites.</strong> Don't do your banking, online shopping, or anything other internet activity that has deeply personal, private information.</p>
<p><strong>Stay patched.</strong> I've covered this before, but make sure your devices have all the latest patches and updates to ensure you're not vulnerable to many known vulnerabilities (yes, even wifi has vulnerabilities).</p>
<p><strong>Consider using your phone.</strong> If there's any doubt at all, most cell phone providers let you use your phone as a hotspot. If you don't have unlimited data, this can potentially push you over your limit. So pay attention!</p>
<p>There are plenty of legitimate public hotspots out there, but it only takes one bad one to steal your data or plant a virus on your computer. Hopefully you're now more aware than you already were and will stay safe.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 09</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-09/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-09/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/43/advent-09.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>secure your home wifi/router</strong></p>
<p>If you don't have high-speed internet at home, today's tip probably won't be for you. Also, how do you survive?&nbsp;Anyway, here are some things you can do to shore up your home wifi router:</p>
<p><strong>Change Default Password</strong>. Your Internet Service Provider (ISP) probably preset the administrator username and password. Log in (using their instructions provided) and change the password. If you have an option to change the admin username, do that too! Many times, the default username/password are universal and can be found on the internet.</p>
<p><strong>Enable Network Encryption</strong>. In order to keep your home network traffic secure and private, you'll want to turn on WPA or (ideally) WPA2 encryption. Each router has different instructions on how to do this.</p>
<p><strong>Change Default SSID</strong>. Your Service Set ID (SSID) is the name of your network and might be set to the manufacturer's default name. Pick a new, unique name for your network to show that you take the time to configure your network properly.</p>
<p><strong>Disable Broadcast SSID</strong>. Now that you know the name of your network, turn off broadcast so that people can't easily find your network without knowing the name. While this doesn't necessarily protect your network, it does hide it making it a little harder to crack.</p>
<p><strong>Advanced Options</strong>. Depending on your level of comfort, consider turning on the firewall (if it's not already) and/or enabling MAC address filtering. These steps will ensure nobody can remotely connect to your router (other than your ISP) and only devices you specify will even be able to connect to the router.</p>
<p>You've taken huge steps in securing your home network and should be able to rest relatively easy knowing you're browsing safely.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 08</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-08/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-day-08/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/42/advent-08.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/34">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>change your passwords</strong></p>
<p>Ideally you've chosen and setup a <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/41">password manager</a>. If not, this part will not be as easy ... but still necessary. Changing your passwords&nbsp;will also be a time consuming process but&nbsp;one that should be ongoing in your life.</p>
<p>As stated previously, the old school of thought was that you should change your password fairly frequently, like every 90 days. New wisdom says only change your password when there's been evidence of a breach of login information. I'm a little more conservative and don't see the harm in changing your passwords annually ... especially if you're using a password manager; it will do all the heavy lifting for you! I feel annually strikes a good balance and minimizes data loss in case of a breach.</p>
<p>If you do use a&nbsp;password manager, it can generate a password with any parameters you give it. I recommend 16-20 characters (or more if the site supports it) and a mix of as many different types of characters as possible. If you have the option to&nbsp;<strong>not</strong> use dictionary or pronouncable words, I suggest you do&nbsp;that too just for an extra layer of security. Again, the point is to have ridiculously hard passwords to guess, and let your password manager remember it for you. Try to manually remember <strong>iJBblxg6@%Ur95VNj0uz</strong> for just one site and now think about&nbsp;how many sites with which you actually have an account.&nbsp;<em>Just don't forget your master password!</em></p>
<p>If you're not using a password manager, then try to stick with memorable passphrases or even just use three random words that you'll remember. Most sites allow all ASCII characters, even spaces, so&nbsp;<strong>round blue bananas</strong> would be a valid password and easier to remember than the password generated <strong>iJBblxg6@%Ur95VNj0uz</strong>. Of course, it likely won't meet the password requirements of most sites ... so you'll have to mix it up a little and&nbsp;<em>still</em> remember it.</p>
<p>Also important, use a different password/passphrase for every site or service with which you have an account (which is <em>very</em> easy to do with a password generator ... are you seeing a theme yet?). For example, if your credentials are stolen in a data breach at&nbsp;Uber.com, <em>hypothetically,</em>&nbsp;and you reused that&nbsp;password everywhere, then the hackers potentially have your login information for every site you visit. Use a different password everywhere (or one master password for your password generator ... okay I'll stop now)!</p>
<p>Now you know how to make a good password; so&nbsp;get out there and do it. In my opinion, you should make a habit of changing your password every year on every site you visit. Put it in your calendar and then just try to break it up over the course of a week or so. Make the effort to visit 5-10 of your sites per day and change your account passwords. It shouldn't take more than 15 minutes to go through that many&nbsp;sites, so you won't spend more than a couple hours over the course of one week per year. That's a pretty small investment to help keep your digital data secure.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cybersecurity Advent - Day 07</title>
        <author>
            <name>Teejay</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-07/"/>
        <id>http://git.notunremarkable.me/cybersecurity-advent-07/</id>
            <category term="Security"/>

        <updated>2017-12-07T09:51:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://git.notunremarkable.me/media/posts/41/advent-07.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Today's <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-intro">Cybersecurity tip</a> is:&nbsp;<strong>use a password manager</strong></p>
<p>For a long time, you probably heard that your password should be a mix of upper, lower, special characters, and numbers and that you needed to change it every two or three months. Oh, and you can't re-use any of the last 30 passwords you've ever used or use any part of a real word or any other number of ridiculous requirements.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fortunately, convential wisdom has changed. Analysis of a decade's worth of data showed that those super complex, constantly changing passwords didn't do much to help. Instead, the new guidelines recommend being more <em>user</em> friendly (hooray!). Long passwords with complexity is still important, but testing those passwords against lists of dictionary passwords and known compromised passwords. And of course, you still need unique passwords for every account you have.&nbsp;In reality, people can't remember that many unique passwords&nbsp;... even with <a href="https://www.passwordping.com/surprising-new-password-guidelines-nist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"looser" guidelines</a>. That's where password managers come in.</p>
<p>The idea of a (good) password manager is that you only need to remember your secure&nbsp;<em>master password</em> and let the password manager handle remembering all the passwords for your various accounts. This frees up your mind to remember one&nbsp;truly secure password.</p>
<p>There are several well-known and respected password managers out there, and each has its strengths and weaknesses. While there are a lot of options for password managers (Dashlane, LastPass, 1Password, etc.), the basic functionality of them is similar. Your passwords are stored, encrypted by your master password, either in the cloud or locally to your computer.&nbsp;I've used&nbsp;<a href="https://www.lastpass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LastPass</a>&nbsp;for the last seven years or so. LastPass&nbsp;only encrypts/decrypts my passwords locally, so there's no worry about a breach on their system. I&nbsp;haven't had any issues with performance, and the convenience of having my passwords on my computer and on my mobile device has saved me more than once. Bonus, LastPass supports <a href="../../../../../../../../../cybersecurity-advent-day-06">2FA</a>.</p>
<p>One last thought, I recommend you use a password manager&nbsp;that has a browser extension available. This allows the password manager to fill in form and password information directly on websites you visit. This makes it even more convenient to browse while still staying secure. If you have any specific questions about LastPass or setting (or choosing) your password manager, ask in the comments below.</p>
<p>See you tomorrow!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
